A Guide to the Edwin Beecher Brown Papers, 1920-1985
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Edwin Beecher Brown Papers, 1920-1985
The Library of Virginia
50641
3.6 cubic feet (8 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Edwin Beecher Brown, Staunton.
Biographical Information
Edwin Beecher Brown was born in Huntington, West Virginia on 14 February 1937. He is the son of Dr. Leland Coffey Brown (1906-1980) and Marjorie Lockridge Mower (1908-1989). He attended Staunton Military Academy and the University of Virginia. He earned a law degree in 1962, and then practiced in Princeton and Charleston, West Virginia, and then in Baltimore. Brown then worked in the retail banking group at Citibank in New York City. He married Yaroslava Sofia Sachno (b. 1937) in Washington, DC on 28 April 1962. They now live in Staunton, Virginia.
Rev. Durward Belmont Brown was born near Pruntytown, West Virginia on 12 January 1897. He was the son of Lloyd Wilson Brown (1868-1933) and Mary Ellen Cottrill (1868-1958). He received A.B. and A.M. degrees from Alleghany College in Pennsylvania, and did seminary work in Boston, where he received a S.T.B. degree from Boston University School of Theology. Rev. Brown served charges in Grafton, Morgantown, and Wheeling, West Virginia. He married Dorothy Elizabeth Rine (1904-1983) on 22 October 1929. Rev. Brown died on 3 January 1983.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1920-1985, of Edwin Beecher Brown (b. 1937) of Staunton, Virginia, consisting of genealogical research files used in the publication of his book Descendants of James Brown (Senior) (17__-1833) Who Settled in Augusta County, Virginia Between the South River and the 'Great Road' That Ran from Waynesboro to Greenville to Lexington, Virginia. Most of the material was compiled by Rev. Durward Belmont Brown (1897-1983) of Wheeling, West Virginia. The collection contains census abstracts, correspondence, clippings, family group sheets, genealogical charts and pedigrees, obituaries, photographs, and published sources on the Brown family and the allied lines of Barnes, Cottrill, Gawthrop, Hall, Hiett, Loy, and Scranage who settled in Augusta and Frederick Counties, Virginia, and Illinois, Indiana, Kansas, Nebraska, and West Virginia.
Contents List
- Addresses/Phone Numbers. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alexander. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Allen. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Atkinson (Ohio County, VA). (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bailey. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Barnes. (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
- Beatty. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Biographical and Portrait Cyclopedia of Monongalia, Marion and Taylor Counties, West Virginia. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Borton. (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Boyd/Boyle. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 1 James Brown. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 11 Boyl Brown. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 111 Wilson Boyle Brown. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 111 Wilson Boyle Brown - Heirs. (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
- 1111 James Boyle Brown. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 11111 Lloyd Wilson Brown. (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- 111112 Durward Belmont Brown. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 1111121 Foster Lloyd Brown. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 11111211 Celeste Elaine Brown. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 1111122 Mary Jane (Brown) Madjlessi. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 111113 James Russell Brown. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 1111131 James Luther Brown. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 1111132 Bernard Wilson Brown. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 1111133 Mary Ellen Juanita Brown. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- 11112 Luella (Brown) Hall. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 11113 Bruce Alexander Brown. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- 111131 Lolita Rosamund (Brown) Whiting. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- 1111312 Anne Belinda (Whiting) Newman. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- 1111313 Elinor Elizabeth (Whiting) DeHaven. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- 111133 Juanita Pauline (Brown) Marsh. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- 11114 Dorsey Lee Brown. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- 111141 James Lee Brown. (Box 2, Folder 22)
- 1111411 Leland Page Brown. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- 111142 Martha Virginia (Brown) Hall. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- 11115 George Taylor Brown. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- 1112 Virginia Jane Brown. (Box 2, Folder 26)
- 1113 Christopher Columbus Brown. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- 1114 Jonathan Wilson Brown. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- 11141 William Cather Brown. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- 111413 William Charles Brown. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- 11143 Grace Ethel (Brown) Salter. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- 111431 Alma Mae (Salter) Van Meter. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- 111432 Gladys Hazel (Salter) Cook. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 111433 Thomas Brown Salter. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- 111434 Donald Maurice Salter. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- 11144 Loomis Holden Brown. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 111442 Wilson Harris Brown. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- 111443 Harold Theodore Brown. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- 11145 Virginia (Brown) McGowan. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- 111451 Carolyn Virginia (McGowan) Derks. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- 1116 George Washington Brown. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- 11162 Ota Leona (Brown) Knapp. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- 111622 Marian Elinor (Knapp) Caldwell. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- 11163 George Edison Brown. (Box 3, Folder 18)
- 1118 Charles Wesley Brown. (Box 3, Folder 19)
- 11181 Mary Susan Elizabeth (Brown) Hackenberg. (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
- 111811 John Vernon Hackenberg. (Box 3, Folder 22)
- 111812 Elizabeth Mae Hackenberg. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- 112 Jonathan Brown. (Box 3, Folder 24)
- 1121 Susan Catherine (Brown) Houser. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- 1122 Mary Elizabeth (Brown) Alexander. (Box 3, Folder 26)
- 1123 John Park Smith Brown. (Box 3, Folder 27)
- 1124 Wilson Minor Brown. (Box 3, Folder 28)
- 12 James Brown. (Box 3, Folder 29)
- 121 James Alexander Brown. (Box 3, Folder 30)
- 1218 Isaac Stuart Brown. (Box 3, Folder 31)
- 123 William Bellama Brown. (Box 3, Folder 32)
- 125 Elisha Boyd Brown. (Box 3, Folder 33)
- 125741 Edwin Beecher Brown. (Box 3, Folder 34)
- 126 Isabella Grimes (Brown) Brown. (Box 3, Folder 35)
- 1263 William Lewis Brown. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- 12631 Isabell (Brown) Kirkpatrick. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- 12632 Blanche Irene (Brown) Churchill. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- 12633 Hazel May (Brown) Misterick. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- 12634 Goldie (Brown) McClatchey. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 12636 William Lewis Brown. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- 12639 Fulton Wayne Brown. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- 126396 Robert Fulton Brown. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- 1263(11) Virginia Elvira (Brown) Cook. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- 1263(12) Hugh Boyd Brown. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- 1263(13) Pansy Jennette (Brown) Bohl. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- 1263(14) Josephine (Brown) Caldwell. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- 1263(15) Donald Grover Brown. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- 128 Henry Brown. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- 129 Jacob Brown. (Box 4, Folder 15)
- 12(10) Benjamin Stuart Brown. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- 12(11) Fulton Worthlow Brown. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- 13 Nancy (Brown) Caruthers. (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Brown, Carlos T.. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Brown - Census - Virginia. (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
- Brown - Indiana/Illinois. (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Josias and Alexander Brown. (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Brown - Nebraska. (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Brown Reunions. (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Brown - Unclassified. (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Brown, William Gay, Jr. (1856-1916). (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Cather. (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Correspondence (Not Relatives). (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Cottrell, William - Civil War Record. (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Cottrill. (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
- DeLong. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- England - Foster Lloyd Brown. (Box 5, Folder 5-9)
- England - Foster Lloyd Brown (Oversize). (Box PP Oversize Box 13, Folder n/a)
- Evans, Elsie H.. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Fedorchak, Catherine. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Gawthrop (Folder 1). (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
- Gawthrop (Folder 2). (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Gawthrop (Folder 3). (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Gawthrop-Bull. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Gawthrop-Shroyer. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Gawthrop-Zinn. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Genealogical Charts (Oversize). (Map-case 2, Drawer 12)
- George. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Hall (Folder 1). (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Hall (Folder 2). (Box 6, Folder 9-11)
- Hall (Folder 3). (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
- Hall-Warder. (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Hiatt-Hiett Genealogy and Family History by William Perry Johnson, 1951. (Box 7, Folder n/a)
- Hiett. (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- Loy. (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
- Marietta (see also Hall). (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Marple. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- McCracken. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Mixed Records. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Neal. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Photographs. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- "Poems" by Thomas Gawthrop (Ten Mile, WV). (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Scranage - Indiana. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Scranage - West Virginia. (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
- Smith. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Spence. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Stonier (England). (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Story. (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Stott. (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Wade. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Williamson. (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Wilson. (Box 8, Folder 16)
- "The Wilson Family" - American Genealogical Research Institute, 1972. (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Winterbourne. (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Woolman. (Box 8, Folder 19)